Prince Commemorative Publications, 1991-2018 SC 163
Archives of African American Music and Culture
Prince Commemorative Publications
1991-2018
Archives of African American Music and Culture
Indiana University, Bloomington. Archives of African American Music and Culture
SC 163
1 document case 1 linear foot
A collection of Prince commemorative publications assembled by the AAAMC following the artist's death on April 21, 2016.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically in one series:
Series 1: Periodicals, newspapers, and comics
Biographical / Historical
Performer, producer, and songwriter, Prince was one of the most popular artists of his generation. Though his rise to fame was a slow one, he received widespread recognition for the album 1999 in 1982, leading to more successful hits. His band, The Revolution, was innovative for its multiracial and multi-gendered makeup, and Prince himself tended to mix styles of both black and white music, going from pop and rock to soul and funk, as well as writing the soundtrack albums for Purple Rain and Batman.
Access Restrictions
Use of time-based media materials (audio and video) may require production of listening or viewing copies.
Access to streaming audio, moving image, and full resolution digital image materials may currently be restricted to researchers who can authenticate with an IU account or who are physically present on campus. Remote streaming to individual researchers may be allowed with the completion of applicable forms.
For further information about access to online audiovisual materials, contact AAAMC staff at aaamc@indiana.edu.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased by the AAAMC.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists primarily of magazines and special commemorative publications; some were published prior to the artist's death.
African American musicians; African American rock musicians; Comic books, strips, etc.; Periodicals; Popular Music; Prince
- 1. Periodicals, newspapers, and comics, 1991-2018; 12 Items
  - City Pages: "The Prince Issue", April 27, 2016; 36 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    17-page cover story.
  - DC Comics: "Prince: Alter Ego", 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    First printed Newsstand Edition.
  - Ebony: "Prince Rogers Nelson 1958-2016", June 2016; LXXI (Box 1, Folder 3)
    23-page cover story.
  - Essence: "Prince: A Tribute to His Royal Badness", June 14, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Collector's Edition.
  - Newsweek: "Prince 1958-2016: The Life and Death of a Musical Genius", May 24, 2016; Special #52 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - People: "Celebrating Prince 1958-2016", May 28, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Special Collector's Edition.
  - Rolling Stone: "Prince: The Ultimate Guide to His Music & Legend", 2016 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rolling Stone: "The Prince Issue", May 19, 2016; 1261 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Storm Entertainment's Tribute:"Prince", May 24, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - TIME: "Prince, An Artist's Life 1958-2016", April 29, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Commemorative Edition.
  - Wax Poetics: "The Prince Issue", 2018; 67 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Village Voice: "Prince 1958-2016: Dearly Beloved…", April 27, 2016; LXI (Box 1, Folder 12)